

Software Engineer seeking roles in Software Development, Java 7,MySQL,Oracle,Tomcat 8,Restfull Api,Soap,ISO 8583,Application Programming ,Application Maintenance etc



Current Designation: Software Engineer -Core Java Total Experience: 4 Year(s) 2 Month(s)

Current Company: ModefinServer Pvt Ltd Notice Period: Currently Serving Notice Period Current Location: Bengaluru / Bangalore Highest Degree: B.Tech/B.E. [Computer Science]

Pref. Location: Bengaluru / Bangalore

Functional Area: IT Software - Application Programming /

Maintenance

Role: Software Developer

Industry: IT-Software/Software Services

Marital Status: Married

Key Skills: Software Engineer.Software Developer.Software Development.Application Programming.Application Maintenance, Project Management, Requirement Analysis, Spring, Core Java, JavaScript, Web Services, HTML, SOAP

UI,SOAPSonar

Verified: Email - id Phone Number |

Last Active: 22-Jan-21 Last Modified: 22-Jan-21

Summary

4 +years of experience of Software engineering under Banking Domain

Hands on experience on Core Java (7), Mysql, SQL Server, Linux Environment and Web services.

Rich exposure to System Development Life Cycle (SDLC).

Strong Object Oriented concepts for software design and implementation.

Strong knowledge of Web Applications and Web services.

Experience in developing the mobile and web based applications using Core Java, MySQL and MS-SQL Server.

Strong interpersonal and communication skills with an ability to handle in all the areas to complete mobile or web based applications

Work Experience

ModefinServer Pvt Ltd as Software Engineer -Core Java

Oct 2016 to Till Date

Developing the code as per the requirements

Writing the UI/Business validations for the owned use cases.

Unit testing and integration testing for owning use cases

Handling different types of issuees

Project 1 Rebuilding Of SBM Bank, Kenya

Period: September 2018 - Current

Technology: Core Java, Servlet, JSP, MySQL, Apache Tomcat 7, Jasper Report ISO 8583, SOAP

Overview: SBM Bank is one of the biggest Bank of Kenya which was formely know as Chase Bank. They offer Mobile

Bnaking, Internet Banking (Retail and Corporate), USSD, wallet, Bill Payments, Airtime Topup and many more.

Roles and Responsibilities:

Designing and developing the code as per the requirement.

Involved in developing business logic.

Created Web Services & JSON data for handling requests and for communication between the modules.

Fixed issues and causes related to performances.

Developed complete EFT flow of funds in both Mobile banking and Internet Banking.

Project 2 May Fair Bank-Nairobi, Keny a

Period: January 2017 - August 2018

Technology:Core Java,Servlet,JSP,MySQL,Apache Tomcat 7,Jasper Report ISO 8583,SOAP,Swift Message Integration.

Overview: MayFair Bank is one of our Client of Kenya .They offer Mobile Bnaking, Internet Banking (Retail and

Corporate),Bill

Payments, Airtime Topup and many more.

Team Members: 2

Roles and Responsibilities:

Developed complete Intergration services for Mobile Banking and Intermet Banking

Involved in developing business logic.

Created Web Services using Soap, JSON, XML for handling request for communitions

Implemented the push notifications of all the mobile apps.

Worked on the complete Fund Transfer Module.

Education

UG: B.Tech/B.E. (Computer Science) from kls VDRIT Haliyal in 2015

IT Skills

Skill Name	Version	Last Used	Experience
Spring			
CORE JAVA	7	2020	4 Year(s)
JavaScript			
Web Services, HTML			
Windows 10, Windows Server 2007, Linus			
SQL Server 2000/2005/2008	2008	2019	4 Year(s)
Microsoft ACT			
Soap UI			

Languages Known

Language	Proficiency	Read	Write	Speak
English				
Hindi				
Kannada				

Affirmative Action

Work Authorization

Physically Challenged: No

Job Type: Permanent

Employment Status: Full time